不喜欢坐飞机 是吗?
You don't like flying, do you?
不太喜欢
What gives you that idea?
想知道长途飞行的健身之道吗?
You wanna know the secret to surviving air travel?
在到达目的地之後 把鞋和袜子脱掉
After you get where you're going, take off your shoes and socks.
然後光着脚在地毯上走走 把脚趾蜷起来
Then you walk around on the rug barefoot and make fists with your toes.
把脚趾蜷起来?
Fists with your toes?
是的 听起来很怪 相信我 我已经做了九年了
I know. It sounds crazy. Trust me. I've been doing it for nine years.
是的 先生 比洗澡和喝咖啡更有效
Yes, sir! Better than a shower and a hot cup of coffee.
别害怕 我是警察
It's OK. I'm a cop.
相信我 我已经作了十一年了
Trust me. I've been doing this for 11 years.
我代表机长和工作人员欢迎 你们来洛杉矶
The captain and the crew would like to welcome you to Los Angeles.
祝大家圣诞快乐
Have a very merry Christmas.
《虎胆龙威》
247航班的旅客请到14号登机口登机
Flight 247 to Tucson now boarding at gate 14.
女士先生们
Ladies and gentlemen...
Ladies and gentlemen!
我要祝贺你们大家 你们的努力
I want to congratulate all of you for making this one of the greatest years
使今年成为 中富公司历史上业绩最好的一年
in the history of the Nakatomi Corporation.
我代表首席执行长和公司董事会
On behalf of the Chief Executive Officer, Mr Ozu, and the Board of Directors,
感谢大家 祝你们圣诞快乐 新年快乐
we thank you all and wish you a merry Christmas and a happy New Year!
圣诞快乐 新年快乐
Merry Christmas! Happy New Year!
嘿 荷莉 一起吃晚餐好吗?
Hey, Holly. What about dinner tonight?
哈里 今天是圣诞夜
Harry, it's Christmas Eve.
家人、圣诞树…
Families, stockings...
还有烤栗子?
Chestnuts?
驯鹿和雪人 你怎么不想想这些?
Rudolph and Frosty? Any of these things ring a bell?
实际上 我想的是芬芳美酒 和美味奶酪
Actually, I was thinking more of mulled wine, a nice, aged Brie
还有熊熊的炉火 你明白我的意思吗?
and a roaring fireplace. You know what I'm saying?
吉妮 已经5:40了 去参加派对 喝点香槟吧
Ginny, it's 5:40. Join the party. Have some champagne.
别让我觉得自己在压榨属下
You're making me feel like Ebenezer Scrooge.
非常感谢 你想胎儿会让我喝两杯吧？
Thanks. Do you think the baby can handle a little sip?
开酒馆都没问题
That baby's ready to tend bar.
最後的机会
Last chance.
再见
Bye.
麦克连家 我是露茜·麦克连
McClane residence. Lucy McClane speaking.
你好 露茜·麦克连 和你说话的是妈妈
Hello, Lucy McClane. This is your mother speaking.
妈咪!你什么时候回家?
Mommy! When are you coming home?
很快 不过到时候 你肯定已经睡了
Pretty soon. You'll be in bed when I get there, though.
让鲍琳娜和我通话 好吗?
Let me talk to Paulina, OK, hon?
不要在家里转来转去找礼物哦
And no snooping around the house looking for presents.
爸爸和你一起回家吗?
Is Daddy coming home with you?
哦 我看还是…
Well, we'll see what
让圣诞老人和妈妈来决定吧
Santa and Mommy can do, OK?
叫鲍琳娜来 再见 宝贝
Put Paulina on. Bye, honey.
鲍琳娜
Paulina!
你好 荷莉太太
Hola, Mrs Holly.
嗯 麦克连先生来过电话吗?
Did Mr McClane call?
没有 荷莉太太 没有电话
No, Mrs Holly. No telefono.
也许他上飞机前没时间打
He probably didn't have time before his flight.
你最好还是把客房收拾好
It might be a good idea to make up the spare bedroom
以防万一
just in case.
是 荷莉太太 我已经收拾了
Si, Mrs Holly. I do that already.
没有你我可怎么办 鲍琳娜?
What would I do without you, Paulina?
加州
California!
我是约翰·麦克连
Hey, I'm John McClane.
我是阿盖 你的包车司机
Argyle. I'm your limo driver.
漂亮的熊
Nice bear.
好吧 阿盖 我们现在该干什么?
OK... Argyle. What do we do now?
我还以为你知道呢 我是第一次开这种车
I was hoping you could tell me. It's my first time driving a limo.
没关系 这也是我第一次坐这种车
That's OK. It's my first time riding in one.
放松 这里要什么有什么
Relax. We got everything in this mug.
你看这儿…CD、收音机、电视
Look at this... CD, CB, TV,
电话、小酒吧、录影机
telephone, full bar, VHS.
如果你的朋友要发情 我还能帮他找头母熊
If your friend's hot to trot, I know a few mama bears we can hook up with.
- 或是说他结婚了? - 他结婚了
- Or is he married? - He's married.
好吧 哦 真对不起 清洁工今天放假 没想到你会坐前排
Sorry about that. It's the girl's day off. I didn't know you were gonna sit up front.
你太太住在这儿?
Your lady live out here?
差不多六个月了
About the past six months.
这么说你还住在纽约
Meaning you still live in New York?
你总是有这么多问题吗 阿盖?
You always ask this many questions, Argyle?
对不起 我以前开出租车 总喜欢和别人聊聊
Sorry. I used to drive a cab and people would expect a little chitchat.
- 你离婚了? - 开你的车吧 伙计
- So, you divorced? - Just drive the car, man.
嘿 说吧 你离婚了? 还是分居?她打你吗?
Hey, come on. You divorced? You separated? She beat you up?!
她有份好工作 现在是事业有成
She had a good job. It turned into a great career.
所以她不得不搬到这儿
That meant she had to move here.
- 你脑子挺灵的 阿盖 - 那你干嘛不到这来?
- You're very fast, Argyle. - So, why didn't you come?
你干嘛不和她一起来 伙计?怎么了?
Well? Why didn't you come with her? What's up?
因为我是纽约警察
Because I'm a New York cop.
我还有一堆纽约人渣要抓
I got a backlog of scumbags I'm still trying to put behind bars.
我不能拍拍屁股就离开
I can'tjust go that easy.
换句话说 你觉得她在这儿不会成功
You thought she wasn't gonna make it here
她会回去你身边 那就不用收拾行李了 对吧?
and she'd come crawling back to you so why bother to pack, right?
没错 你的脑子确实很灵 阿盖
Like I said, you're very fast, Argyle.
听听音乐可以吗?
Mind if we hear some tunes?
嘿 真不错
Hey, that'll work.
听听圣诞歌曲好吗?
Don't you got any Christmas music?
这就是圣诞歌曲
This is Christmas music.
等一下你太太见到你 你们紧紧拥抱
So your lady sees you, you run into her arms,
接着音乐响起 从此就幸福生活 是吗?
the music comes up and you live happily ever after, right?
这个计划不错
I can live with that.
如果这招不管用 你要找个地方住吗?
So, if it doesn't work out, you got a place to stay?
对 我要找个地方
I'll find a place.
就这样吧 我把车开到车库去等着 要是成了 就打电话给我
I tell you what. I'll wait in the parking garage. You score, give me a call on the car phone.
我会把你的包放在前台 要是没成功 我就帮你找家旅馆
I'll take your bags to the desk. You strike out, I'll get you a hotel.
- 你这人不错 阿盖 - 给小费的时候别忘了就行
- You're all right, Argyle. - Remember that when you sign for the tip.
- 嗨 - 晚上好
- Hi. - Good evening.
我来找荷莉·麦克连
I'm here to see Holly McClane.
打在那上面就行了
Just type it in there.
可爱的玩具
Cute toy.
是啊 上厕所时 还能帮你拉拉链
Yeah, if you have to take a leak, it'll even help you find your zipper.
天啊
Christ!
第三十层
Thirtieth floor?
开派对那层 现在这座楼里就剩他们了
The party. They're the only ones left.
乘快速电梯 听到嘈杂声就到了
Take the express elevator. Get off where you hear the noise.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 香槟，先生？ - 谢谢
- Champagne, sir? - Yeah, thanks.
哦 对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
圣诞快乐!
Hey! Merry Christmas!
老天!
Jesus.
该死的加州人
Fuckin' California!
嗨 我正在找…
Hi. I'm looking for...
- 荷莉·吉奈萝? - 对
- Holly Gennero. - Yeah.
您肯定是约翰·麦克连
Then you must be John McClane.
我是青木 那辆车还可以吗?
Joe Takagi. How was your ride in?
很好 是您安排的吗?
Nice. I have you to thank for that?
那是最起码我能做的
Seemed the least we could do.
这地方真的不错
Quite a place you have.
等完工後会更好的 还有几层没有建好
It will be if we get it finished. Still several floors under construction.
荷莉到下面去传真一些文件 她马上就回来
Holly went to fax some documents. She should be back any minute.
这边请 她的办公室就在这儿
In the meanwhile, her office is back here.
艾利斯?
Ellis?
我刚想打个电话 这儿的电话最近
I was making a call. This was the nearest phone.
这位是约翰·麦克连
I want you to meet John McClane,
荷莉的丈夫
Holly's husband.
一位警官
Holly's policeman.
艾利斯负责国际发展部
Ellis is in charge of international development.
久仰您的大名
Heard a lot about you.
没擦乾净
You missed some.
您想吃点什么吗?
Can I get you anything?
食物?糕点? 掺水的香槟?
Food? Cake? Some watered-down champagne?
不用 谢谢 我不饿
No, thank you. I'm fine.
真是盛大的聚会
You throw quite a party.
没想到日本人也过圣诞节
I didn't realize they celebrated Christmas in Japan.
我们善於变通 珍珠港没有成功 我们就倾销电器
We're flexible. Pearl Harbor didn't work out, so we got you with tape decks.
实际上 今天是双喜临门 我们今天做成了一笔大买卖
It's sort of a double celebration. We closed a pretty big deal today
荷莉是主要的功臣 我正想…
and a lot of it was due to Holly.
我可要失陪了
I'll be out in a couple of minutes.
约翰…
John.
和大家见过面了?
Have you met everyone?
没有 我们正在监视他
We've been sticking him with spears.
开个玩笑
Of course he has.
她是一名商业天才 非常强硬
She was made for the business. Tough as nails.
我正希望你有赶上那班飞机
I was hoping you made that flight.
给他看看那个表
Show him the watch.
等会儿
Later.
给他看看 你不好意思吗? 这是对她…
Show him. Are you embarrassed? It's a small token of appreciation
努力工作的一点奖赏 是劳力士手表
for all her hard work. It's a Rolex.
我想以後会见到的
I'm sure I'll see it later.
这儿有能梳洗的地方吗?
Is there a place where I could wash up?
当然
Sure.
你得原谅艾利斯 他每年这个时候都很沮丧
You have to forgive Ellis. He gets very depressed this time of year.
他总是认为自己的天赋最高 明白吗?
He thought he was God's greatest gift, you know?
我知道这种人
I know the type.
我想他看上你了
I think he's got his eye on you.
没什么 我看上了他的私人浴室
That's OK. I have my eye on his private bathroom.
你要住在哪儿?事发突然…
Where are you staying? Things happened so fast
我还来不及打电话问你
I didn't get a chance to ask you on the phone.
凯皮·罗伯茨退休到了这儿
Cappy Roberts retired out here.
- 他说我可以去他那儿住 - 凯皮退休了?他住在哪儿?
- He said I could bunk with him. - Cappy retired, huh? Where's he live?
拉摩纳
Romona.
是帕摩纳
Pomona.
帕摩纳
- 帕摩纳 - 对
- Pomona. - Yeah.
天哪 那样时间都花在车上了
You'll be in the car half the time.
我们还是简单一点吧 我有一个空房间
Why don't we make it easy? I have a spare bedroom.
虽然它不算大 可是孩子们…
It's not huge or anything, but
愿意和你在一起
the kids would love to have you at the house.
他们愿意吗?
They would, huh?
我也愿意
I would, too.
对不起
Sorry.
我想你
I missed you.
但是不包括我的姓氏在内 嗯?
Didn't miss my name, though, huh?
也许在签支票的时候能想起来
Except maybe when you're signing checks?
你什么时候开始姓吉奈萝了?
Since when did you start using Ms Gennero?
这是一家日本公司 他们认为 已婚女人不可靠…
This is a Japanese company. They figure a married woman's...
你是结过婚的 荷莉 你嫁给我了
You are a married woman.
- 你怎么又说起这个了? - 我们还没有谈完
- This conversation again? - We never finished this conversation.
- 我有了一次机会 必须把握它 - 对 不管是什么结果
- I had an opportunity. I had to take it. - No matter what it did to our marriage.
- 也许它改变了你对婚姻的理解 - 你根本对我的理解不了解…
- It changed your idea of our marriage. - You have no clue what my idea...
我完全清楚你对婚姻的理解
I know exactly what your idea of our marriage should be.
吉奈萝小姐 我…
Ms Gennero, I...
对不起
Excuse me.
嗨
Hi.
青木先生正在找你 他想让你为大家说几句
Mr Takagi is looking for you. He wants you to say something to the troops.
谢谢
Thank you.
我要走了
Speech time.
我一会儿就回来
Be back in a few minutes.
真是好样的 约翰
That was great, John.
干的好 真成熟
Good job. Very mature.
贾霸夺下篮板 传给沃斯 接着是格林 再传约翰逊
So Kareem rebounds. Feeds Worthy on the break, over to AC, to Magic,
又传给沃斯
then back to Worthy.
砰!两分
Boom! Two points.
行了
We're in.
(自底层至29层关闭)
(太平洋电话公司雇员专用)
真傻
Son of a bitch.
把脚趾头蜷起来
Fists with your toes.
嘿 阿盖?
Yeah, Argyle?
你的事怎么样了?
How's it going?
很好 你在哪儿?
All right. Where are you?
我在车库享受呢 你和太太说了些什么?
Down at the garage. What's with you and your lady?
还没定下来呐
The vote's not in yet.
阿盖?
Argyle?
麦克 怎么了?喂!
Mac, you there? Hello?
你知道号码 我等着
You know the number. Use it.
保持镇静 没事的
Stay calm. Everything's going to be fine.
没事的
Everything's going to be fine.
妈的
Shit!
冷静
Think.
女士先生们
Ladies and gentlemen.
由於中富公司在全球的 长期贪婪掠夺
Due to the Nakatomi Corporation's legacy of greed around the globe
他们将遭到强大力量的惩罚
they're about to be taught a lesson in the real use of power.
你们将作为见证人
You will be witnesses.
现在…
Now...
请问哪位是青木先生?
where is Mr Takagi?
约瑟夫·高木
Joseph Yashinobo Takagi,
1937年生於京都
born Kyoto, 1937.
别动
Don't move.
全家於1939年 移民至加州的圣佩德罗
Family emigrated to San Pedro, California, 1939,
1942年至43年在拘留营度过
interned at Manzanar, 1942 to '43,
1955年获得加州大学的奖学金
scholarship student, University of California,
195年
1955.
1962年获史丹福大学法学学位
Law degree, Stanford, 1962.
1970年哈佛工商管理硕士学位
MBA, Harvard, 1970.
中富贸易公司总裁
President, Nakatomi Trading.
中富投资集团副主席
Vice Chairman, Nakatomi Investment Group...
够了
Enough.
为人之父
And father
有五个孩子
of five.
我就是青木
I am Takagi.
您好
How do you do?
很高兴认识您
It's a pleasure to meet you.
32楼还没完工 33楼是电脑室
32... construction, 33... computers.
漂亮的西装
Nice suit.
约翰菲利普 伦敦店
John Phillips, London.
我自己也有两套
I have two myself.
据说阿拉法特也在那儿买衣服
Rumor has it Arafat buys his there.
- 这边吗? - 向左转
- This way? - On the left.
“当亚历山大见到他辽阔的帝国时
"And when Alexander saw the breadth of his domain
他哭了 因为他已经无可征服”
he wept, for there were no more worlds to conquer."
这就是古典教育的好处
The benefits of a classical education.
真是太美了
That's beautiful.
我小的时候也喜欢做模型
I always enjoyed to make models when I was a boy.
精确无误 不能放过任何细节
The exactness, the attention to every conceivable detail.
太美了
It's beautiful.
这就是你来的目的? 我们在印尼的计划?
Is this what this is all about? Our project in Indonesia?
你和同夥们都想错了
Contrary to what you people may think,
我们想发展那个地区 而不是剥削
we're going to develop that region, not exploit it.
我完全相信 我读过《福布斯》杂志的报导
I believe you. I read the article in Forbes.
青木先生
Mr Takagi...
我可以谈上一整天 工业化和男性时装
I could talk about industrialization and men's fashions all day
但是我想工作更重要
but I'm afraid work must intrude
我的同事西奥有些问题要问你
and my associate here has some questions for you.
实际上是要你做几道填空题
Sort of fill-in-the-blanks questions, actually.
我没有这密码!
I don't have that code.
你们闯进来就是为了电脑?
You broke in here to access our computer?
你们得到的任何资讯 明天早上都会被东京方面更改
Any information you get, when they wake up in Tokyo, they'll change it.
你根本无法勒索我方高层 威胁或者敲诈…
You won't be able to blackmail our executives...
坐下!
Sit... down!
青木先生 我对你的电脑不感兴趣
Mr Takagi, I'm really not interested in your computer.
但是我需要密码
But I need the code key
我感兴趣的是你锁在金库里
because I am interested in the $640 million
价值6.4亿美元的可转让债券
in negotiable bearer bonds that you have locked in your vault
而金库受电脑控制
and the computer controls the vault.
你们只要钱?
You want money?
你们算什么恐怖分子?
What kind of terrorists are you?
谁说我们是恐怖分子?
Who said we were terrorists?
这笔债券最多也只有
The bonds represent, at most,
您们财团十天的运作资金
10 days' operating capital for your parent organization.
小菜一盘
It's really no more than a temporary inconvenience.
现在…
Now...
请说出密码
The code, please.
你有密码也没用 金库共有七道安全设施
It's useless to you. There are seven safeguards on our vault.
密码只是其中一道 你永远也打不开
The code key's only one of them. You won't get it open.
那您就更没有理由 不告诉我们了
Then there's no reason not to tell it to us.
- 不出所料 - 还没完呢
- I told you. - It's not over yet.
您的西装很漂亮 青木先生
It's a very nice suit, Mr Takagi.
弄脏了会很可惜
It would be a shame to ruin it.
我会从一数到三
I'm going to count to three.
绝不会有四
There will not be a four.
说出密码
Give me the code.
一
One,
二
two,
- 三 - 我说过了 我不知道!
- three... - I don't know it.
坐飞机到东京去问社长吧
Get on ajet to Tokyo and ask the chairman.
听我说 你只能杀了我
You'll just have to kill me.
好吧
OK.
看来只好费些力气了
We do it the hard way.
托尼 你来打扫这里
Tony, dispose of that.
卡尔 你最好到设备层去 检查一下亨利的进展
Karl, check on Heinrich up on the machine floor.
没人
Nothing.
去找亨利
See to Heinrich.
现在…
Now...
你能破解密码吗?
you can break the code?
你带我来只是因为我的 相貌英俊吗?
You didn't bring me along for my charming personality.
阿盖 希望你听到枪声 正在报警
Argyle, tell me you heard the shots. You're calling the police right now.
我当然会去找你
Of course I'm still coming by later.
宝贝 我以前骗过你吗?
Sweetheart, have I ever lied to you?
我的老板? 他还以为我去了赌城呢
My boss thinks I'm on my way to Vegas.
尤里 爬到管道上面去
Uli, get up on the pipes.
马可 你到对面去
Marco, you go through here.
我把导线扔给你
I'll throw you the cord.
汉斯 我们在楼顶
Hans, we're on the roof.
接着
Here.
抓到了 尤里
Uli.
破解密码需要三十分钟
30 minutes to break the code,
五道机械锁则需要 至少两到两个半小时
two hours, two and a half hours for the five mechanicals, at the minimum.
但是第七道锁 我也无法对付
The 7th lock, however, is out of my hands.
你说什么?
I'm sorry?
第七道锁 是电磁密封装置
The 7th lock... the electromagnetic seal.
在这里面无法切断电路
The circuits cannot be cut locally.
相信我
Trust me.
你他妈的为什么不阻止他们 约翰?
Why the fuck didn't you stop him, John?
因为这样你也死定了 是吗?
'Cause then you'd be dead, too, asshole.
冷静 混蛋 冷静!
Think, goddamn it! Think!
楼内有火警警报
We've got a fire alarm.
打119
Call 911.
告诉他们警卫的名字 和消防密码 取消警报
Give them the guard's name and cancel the alarm.
然後毁掉火警系统
Then disable the sys...
艾迪 警报是哪一层发出的?
Eddie, on what floor did the alarm go off?
我们能走了吗?
Shall we go?
行
Yes.
嘿 过来 宝贝 到爸爸这来
Hello, baby. Come to Papa. Come on.
过来 哈!
Come on, baby.
宝贝 宝贝 过来 宝贝!
到爸爸这来 让我亲亲你他妈的小狗
Come on, baby. Come to Papa. I'll kiss your fuckin' Dalmatian.
哦 你们这些蠢货
You stupid motherfuckers! No! No!
哦!不!把车头掉过来
Turn the fuckin' truck around!
火警已经解除了 朋友
The fire has been called off, my friend.
没人会来帮你的
No one is coming to help you.
你应该出来和大家在一起
You might as well come out and join the others.
我保证绝不伤害你
I promise I won't hurt you.
放下枪 白痴 我是警察
Drop it, dickhead. It's the police.
你不会伤害我
You won't hurt me.
哦 是吗?为什么?
Yeah? Why not?
因为你是警察
Because you're a policeman.
警察要遵守规定
There are rules for policemen.
对 我的上司也这么说
Yeah, that's what my captain keeps telling me.
(密码有效 一号锁解除)
(继续操作吗?)
大傻瓜 当然继续
Bet your ass I wish to proceed.
全世界有九百万恐怖分子
Nine million terrorists in the world
我却杀了一个 脚比我妹妹还小的家伙
and I gotta kill one with feet smaller than my sister.
我希望这是一次 职业的、有效的、合作性的接触
I wanted this to be professional, efficient, adult, cooperative.
不要问的太多
Not a lot to ask.
可惜 你们的青木先生不这样看
Mr Takagi did not see it that way
所以他的余生无法和大家在一起了
so he won't be joining us for the rest of his life.
事态的发展是由你们决定的
We can go any way you want it.
你们可以走出去 也可以被抬出去
You can walk out of here or be carried out
请不要心存幻想 我们是主宰者
but have no illusions... we are in charge.
现在大家来决定吧
So... decide now, each of you
请记住…
and please remember...
任何可能的情况我们都考虑到了
we have left nothing to chance.
拿回来!
Get them back!
现在我有一支机关枪
"Now I have a machine gun".
呵 呵 呵
HO-HO-HO.
是漏网的警卫?
A security guard we missed?
警卫都是吃养老金的胖老头 不 肯定另有他人
They're usually tired, old policemen. No, this is something else.
我们必须采取措施 汉斯
We have to do something, Hans.
是的 是的
Yes, we do.
告诉卡尔 他弟弟死了 叫他下来
Tell Karl his brother is dead. Tell him to come down.
法兰柯 你和佛里把屍体抬到楼上
Franco, Fritz, take the body upstairs and out of sight.
我不要让人质乱想
I don't want the hostages to think too much.
我要报仇!
I want blood!
会有机会的! 不过先让亨利装好炸药
You'll have it, but let Heinrich plant the detonators
弄开金库 我们报警後
and Theo prepare the vault. After we call the police,
到时你要把大楼拆了都行
you can tear the building apart looking for this man
在那之前 我们不能改变计划!
but, until then, do not alter the plan!
如果他改变我们的计划呢？
And if he alters it?
你认为是怎么回事?
What do you think?
有些不对头
Something's wrong.
警察？
Cops?
- 是约翰 - 约翰?
- John. - John?
天哪!他会把一切都搞糟的! 他以为自己在干什么?
He can fuck this up. What does he think he's doing?
在工作
His job.
胡闹!他的工作在三千英里之外
Bullshit. His job's 3,000 miles away.
没有他 我们还有机会离开这个地方
Without him, we still have a chance to get out of here.
去跟青木说吧
Tell that to Takagi.
求救!求救! 有人听到的话转到9号频道
Mayday, anyone copying channel nine.
恐怖分子占领了中富大厦 劫持了至少三十名人质
Terrorists have seized the Nakatomi building and are holding 30 people hostage.
重复 恐怖分子人数不详
I repeat. Unknown number of terrorists,
六个或更多人 携有自动武器
six or more armed with automatic weapons at Nakatomi Plaza,
在中富大厦，世纪城
Century City.
哪里最适合发送信号?
Where's the best place to transmit?
楼顶!
The roof!
快!快!
Go! Go!
和刚才的火警来自同一地点
It's the same address as that fire signal.
我来应付
I'll handle it.
注意 不管你是谁 这个频道仅供紧急呼叫使用
Attention, whoever you are, this channel is reserved for emergency calls only.
这不是玩笑 小姐! 我听起来像在订比萨吗?
No fucking shit, lady! Do I sound like I'm ordering a pizza?
除了我谁也不许杀他
No one kills him but me.
他们已经杀了一个人质
They have already killed one hostage.
他们正在巩固阵地 而你却和我在这儿废话!
They are fortifying their positions while you're jerkin' me off!
先生 我已经说过了 这是一个专用频道
Sir, I've already told you. This is a reserved channel.
如果有紧急情况 请你打119
If this is an emergency call, dial 911 on your telephone.
否则我将视此为违法活动
Otherwise, I'll report this as an FCC violation.
好啊!举报我! 他妈的快来这儿抓我啊!
Fine! Come down here and arrest me! Just send the police now!
调一辆警车去那儿看看
See if a black and white can drive by.
我还以为你们只吃甜甜圈
Thought you guys just ate doughnuts.
这是给我太太买的
They're for my wife.
她怀孕了
She's pregnant.
包起来
Bag it.
真会选时间
Big time.
谢谢
Thanks.
中心呼叫林肯30 完毕
Dispatch to 8-Lincoln-30. Over.
我是林肯30 请讲 完毕
This is 8-Lincoln-30.
请前往中富大厦 调查非法闯入案件
Investigate a code two at Nakatomi Plaza, Century City.
林肯30呼叫中心 我这就去
8-Lincoln-30 to Dispatch. I'm on my way.
你们好
Girls.
妈的 电梯跑哪儿去了?
Shit! Where the fuck is it?
天啊!
Oh, my God.
他在电梯井里
He's in the elevator shaft.
很好 电梯已经被锁住了 他逃不了
Perfect. The elevators are locked off. He can't escape.
把他关在里面 然後回来
Shut him in and come back down.
哦 妈的
Oh, fuck.
卡尔 警察可能就要到了
Karl, the police are probably on their way already.
卡尔?
Karl?
天啊!
Christ.
我可以骗过他们 但不能让他们听见枪声
I can stall them, but not if they hear gunshots.
把他关起来 他就无计可施了
If you lock him in, he'll be neutralized...
“到西海岸来吧 我们聚聚…”
"Come out to the coast! We'll get together, have a few laughs."
现在我才知道鼹鼠的感受
Now I know what a TV dinner feels like.
卡尔，警察来了
你们也该来了
Well, it's about time.
没有骚乱的迹象 中心
No signs of disturbance, Dispatch.
收到 林肯30 也许是骚扰电话
Roger. Possible crank call.
再检查一遍该地区，确认情形
Check the area again and confirm.
是谁在开车 夜魔侠吗?
Who's driving this car? Stevie Wonder?
大厦里面有警卫
I do see a guard inside.
我要进去仔细看看
I'm gonna go in for a closer look.
收到 林肯30 小心进行
Use caution.
艾迪
Eddie?
我早有预感你会呼叫我
I had a feelin' you'd be callin'.
晚上好 警官 我能帮什么忙吗?
Evenin', officer. What can I do for you?
这是一次假警报
We had that false alarm.
是该死的电脑让你又白跑一趟
You ask me, that computer sent you on another wild-goose chase.
自从这套系统安装好以後 它就一直故障
They been chasing bugs in this system ever since they installed it.
圣母大学领先南加州大学
...Notre Dame on top of USC.
哦 妈的!
Aw, shit!
我花了五十块钱赌他们赢
I got 50 bucks bet on them assholes.
快点 快点 大队人马在哪儿?
Come on, come on, where's the fucking cavalry?
我可以四处看看吗 老兄?
Mind if I look around?
行 随便
Help yourself.
现在第一节只剩二十七秒钟了
27 seconds left in this first period. Seven to nothing, Notre Dame.
这玩意真硬
I'll put this fuckin'...
不准动 混蛋! 放下枪!
Freeze, motherfucker! Drop it!
把枪放下!
Don't shoot!
- 快放下! - 别开枪
- Put the gun down! - OK! Don't shoot!
他妈的快点放下!
Drop that fuckin' gun!
马可 趴下!
Marco, down!
还查什么呀
To hell with this!
你完蛋了!
You are done!
没有桌子了 你还想藏哪儿?
No more table! Where are you going, pal?
下次有机会开枪时 千万别犹豫
Next time you have a chance to kill someone, don't hesitate.
多谢你的建议
Thanks for the advice.
- 对不起打搅了 - 没问题
- Sorry to waste your time. - No problem at all.
- 圣诞快乐 - 也祝你圣诞快乐
- Merry Christmas. - Merry Christmas to you.
看在老天份上…
Oh, for the love...
林肯30呼叫中心
8-Lincoln-30 to Dispatch.
林肯30 请讲
Go ahead.
又白跑一趟 中富大厦一切正常 完毕
A wild-goose chase at Nakatomi Plaza. Everything here's OK. Over.
该死!
Shit!
我的天!
Goddamn it! Jesus H Christ!
欢迎加入派对 老兄!
Welcome to the party, pal!
马上派人来 妈的
Get someone here now, goddamn it!
我在中富大厦 遭到自动武器袭击
Policeman under automatic rifle fire at Nakatomi!
我请求立即支援!
I need backup assistance now!
马上来! 听见没有?马上!
Now, goddamn it! Now!
莫妮卡 我会搞定餐馆预约
Monica, I can get us a table.
沃夫冈和我是很好的朋友
Wolfgang and I are very close friends.
我采访过他 保证没问题
I interviewed him!
重复 有警察需要增援…
Repeat. Officer needs assistance at...
我在中富大厦! 我的车被打成筛子啦!
I'm at Nakatomi Plaza. They're turning my car into Swiss cheese!
我需要支援 快点来! 他妈的 马上!
I need backup assistance now! Now, goddamn it! Now!
没想到听到警笛这么高兴!
Never thought I'd love to hear that sound.
大家不要紧张 只是一点麻烦 没什么
All of you relax. This is a matter of inconvenient timing, that's all.
警方的行动是不可避免的 而且是必要的
Police action was inevitable... and, as it happens, necessary.
就让他们在外面瞎撞吧
So, let them fumble about outside and stay calm.
这只是一个开始
This is simply the beginning.
我想我已经说过 要保持无线电静默
I told you all I wanted radio silence until...
是吗 我很抱歉 汉斯 我没收到这条指令
I'm very sorry, Hans. I didn't get that message.
也许你应该贴在公告板上
Maybe you should have put it on a bulletin board.
我想既然我干掉了 托尼、马可和他的朋友
I figured since I waxed Tony and Marco and his friend here,
你和卡尔还有法兰柯 也许会感到寂寞
I figured you and Karl and Franco might be lonely
所以我想和你聊聊
so I wanted to give you a call.
他怎么会知道这么多?
How does he know so much about us?
你真是一个好人
That's very kind of you.
我想你就是那位不速之客
I assume you are our mysterious party crasher.
作为一名警卫
You are most troublesome
你可真是称职
for a security guard.
抱歉 汉斯 你猜错了
Sorry, Hans. Wrong guess.
要不要再猜一次 说不准还能得分
Would you like to go for double jeopardy?
这对你的健康没好处
These are very bad for you.
你到底是谁?
Who are you, then?
我只是一只讨厌的苍蝇 汉斯
Just the fly in the ointment, Hans.
一只捣乱的猴子
The monkey in the wrench,
喉咙里的一根刺
the pain in the ass.
去查查别的人 别用对讲机
Check on all the others. Don't use the radio.
看看马可是不是真的死了 查出还有谁失联
See if he's lying about Marco and find out if anyone else is missing.
不速之客先生?
Mr Mystery Guest,
你还在吗?
are you still there?
对 我还在
Yeah, I'm still here
你想打开大门迎接我吗?
unless you want to open the front door for me.
哦 我想不会
No, I'm afraid not,
你给我带来了麻烦
but you have me at a loss.
你知道我的名字 但是你是谁?
You know my name, but who are you?
你是不是小的时候电影看多了?
Just another American who saw too many movies as a child?
还是破产家庭的孤儿?
Another orphan of a bankrupt culture
自以为是大英雄? 蓝波?狄龙警长?
who thinks he's John Wayne, Rambo, Marshal Dillon?
其实我一直崇拜牛仔罗伊
I was always partial to Roy Rogers, actually.
特别是那件亮闪闪的上衣
I liked those sequined shirts.
你真的以为 能和我们对抗吗 牛仔?
Do you really think you have a chance against us, Mr Cowboy?
等着瞧 混蛋
Yippee-ki-yay, motherfucker.
给我一部新闻车 我能胜过其他人!
I'll beat everyone if I get a remote.
山姆 我还没拿到新闻稿
Sam, I don't have the new pages.
哈维 保持镇静 好吗?
Harvey, keep your pants on.
山姆 我求你了
Sam, I'm begging you.
西蒙已经乘新闻车出去了 我让他先去看看
Simon's with the remote. I'll tell him to swing by.
我不想让给西蒙!
I won't sit on this!
这是我的新闻 我马上就要去!
This is my story! I'm going out there!
好啦 听着 山姆 我告诉你
Look, Sam. Tell you what.
如果你不给我一辆车 我就去偷一辆
You don't give me a truck, I'll steal a truck.
- 嘿 少说两句 索伯 - 闭嘴 哈维!
- Give us a break, Thornburg. - Eat it, Harvey!
四 三 二…
...four, three, two,
一
one.
哈维 已经开始直播了
Harvey, we're on the air.
晚上好 我是哈维·强森
Good evening. This is Harvey Johnson.
我是盖儿·华伦斯 现在是十点
And I'm Gail Wallens. This is Nightline News at 10.
新闻节目 首先播报要闻
Our top stories on this Christmas Eve...
给你五号车 赶快滚蛋
Take truck number five and get outta here.
他没骗人 马可躺在大街上
He wasn't lying about Marco. He's down on the street.
另一个是亨利
The other man was Heinrich
他的包不见了
and his bag is missing.
雷管在他那儿
He had the detonator.
西奥
Theo.
我们有麻烦了 你的进展如何?
We may have some problems. How's our schedule?
开了三道 还有四道
Three down, four to go.
那就别浪费时间和我说话
Then don't waste time
我是洛杉矶警察局的鲍尔警官
talking to me.
如果那个报警的人
This is Sergeant Al Powell
能收到这个频道
of the LA Police Department. If the person who radioed for help
请你马上回话
can hear me on this channel, acknowledge this transmission.
我再说一遍
I say again,
如果刚才报警的人能收到这个频道
if the person who radioed for help can hear me,
请你马上回话
acknowledge this transmission!
我听到了 你就是开车的人?
I read you, pal. You the guy in the car?
那位差点完蛋的
What's left of him.
你能说明身份吗?
Can you identify yourself?
现在不行 以後再说
Not now. Maybe later.
仔细听着 频道上有其他人 他们都喜欢扣扳机
Listen fast. This is a party line. The neighbors got itchy trigger fingers.
情况如下 三十层有大约三十名人质
Here's the deal. You got 30 or so hostages on the 30th floor.
匪徒的头目叫汉斯
The leader's name is Hans.
我们得让他闭嘴 他什么都说了
We have to shut him up. He's telling them everything!
别管他 我正等着联邦调查局
Let him. I'm waiting for the FBI.
在那之前 随便他浪费时间
He can waste as much time as he likes
不过我们得找到那个背包
but we must find the bag, Fritz.
弗里兹 去帮尤里
They have a freakin'arsenal here.
我们必须夺回雷管
We must have the detonators.
他们有导弹和自动武器
They got missiles and enough plastic explosives to orbit Arnold Schwarzenegger.
炸药多到能把阿诺炸上天
They're down to nine, counting the skydiver you met.
他们现在还剩九个 算上刚才那位空中飞人
These guys are mostly European judging by their clothing labels and...
这些人大多数是欧洲人 从他们的服装…
cigarettes.
…和香菸品牌看得出来
They're well-financed and very slick.
他们手头富裕 非常专业
How do you know that?
你是怎么知道这些的?
I've seen enough phony IDs in my time
我见过许多假证件
to recognize the ones they got must have cost a fortune.
他们的肯定花了不少钱
Add all that up, I don't know what the fuck it means
总之 我不知道 这意味着什么
but you got some bad-ass perpetrators and they're here to stay.
但是你们在这儿遇到的 都是职业高手
I hear you, partner. LA's finest are on it,
我明白了 老兄 洛杉矶警局的精锐就到了
so light 'em if you got 'em.
早就点上了 老兄
Way ahead of you, partner.
我怎么叫你?
So what do I call you?
叫我…
Call me...
罗伊
Roy.
听我说 罗伊 如果你漏了什么
Listen up, Roy, if you think of anything else
千万别客气
don't be shy, OK?
找一个安全的地方藏起来 其它的事我们来处理，清楚吗?
In the meantime, find a safe place and let us do your job.
交给你了 艾尔
They're all yours, Al.
谁在和他们谈判?
Who's talking to 'em?
是我 长官 鲍尔警官 艾尔·鲍尔
I am, sir. Sergeant Powell. Al Powell.
杜恩·罗宾森 怎么回事? 这些混蛋想要什么?
Dwayne Robinson. What's the deal? What do these pricks want?
对那些恐怖分子
If you mean the terrorists,
我们一无所知
we haven't heard a peep from them.
那你刚才在和谁通话?
Who have you been talking to?
我也不清楚 他不想说他的名字
We don't know. He won't give us his name.
但应该就是报警的那个人
But he appears to be the one who phoned.
他杀了一名恐怖分子 而且他说还杀了另外两个
He's killed one terrorist and claims he capped two others.
他说?
He claims?
鲍尔 你有没有想过…
Powell, has it occurred to you
是恐怖分子假扮来骗你?
he could be one of the terrorists
或是什么疯子?
or some nutcase in there?
我认为不是 长官 实际上我认为他是警察
I don't think so. In fact, I think he's a cop,
也许不是洛杉矶的 但必是一名警察
maybe not LAPD, but he's definitely a badge.
- 你怎么知道? - 直觉 还有他说的话
- How do you know that? - A hunch... things he said
比如他能分辨假证件
like being able to spot a phony ID.
天啊 鲍尔!
Jesus Christ, Powell!
连酒吧的招待都会做!
He could be a bartender for all we know!
记者来了
TV's here.
哦 该死
Oh, shit.
我有个要求
I have a request.
哪个笨蛋让你当老大?
What idiot put you in charge?
就是你
You did
你杀了我的老板 现在我最大
when you murdered my boss. Now everybody's looking to me.
我并不想要这个责任 因为我不想这么靠近你
Personally, I'd pass on the job. I don't enjoy being this close to you.
说吧
Go on.
外面有一位怀孕的妇女
We have a pregnant woman.
放心 她还有几周才会生
Relax. She's not due for a couple of weeks
但是坐在地板上对她的背不好
but sitting on that rock isn't doing her any good.
请你准许让她到 办公室的沙发上坐
So I would like permission to move her to an office with a sofa.
我们可以把沙发搬出来 不是吗?
No, but I'll have a sofa brought out. Good enough?
很好
Good enough.
如果你怕脏的话 最好开始让我们分组去上厕所
And unless you like it messy, I'd start bringing us in groups to the bathroom.
对 你说的对 没问题
Yes. You're right. It will be done.
还有别的事吗?
Was there something else?
没有 谢谢
No, thank you.
青木先生很会选人 你是…
Mr Takagi chose his people well, Mrs?
吉奈萝
Gennero.
吉奈萝小姐
Ms Gennero.
我们中断节目 播出特别新闻报导
We interrupt this program for a special bulletin.
理查·索伯在世纪城 为您现场报导
This is Richard Thornburg live from Century City.
今晚 洛杉矶也成为…
Tonight, Los Angeles has joined the sad and worldwide fraternity of cities
遭受国际恐怖分子威胁的
whose only membership requirement
全球城市之列
is to suffer the anguish of international terrorism.
大约两个小时以前 一群身份不详的恐怖分子
Approximately two hours ago, an unidentified group of men
占领了中富大厦 封锁了所有入口和出口
seized control of the Nakatomi building, sealing off all entrances and exits.
电话线全部被切断 现在唯一的通讯手段
All telephone lines have been cut and the only communication now possible
就是无线电对讲机
has been through the use of CB communicators
显然是由恐怖分子带来的
which the group brought with them.
警方称占领这座大厦的暴徒…
According to official sources, the perpetrators of this building siege...
第五组 在主入口处待命
Unit five, hold your position.
查理那一组在停车场…
We got Charlie unit in position by the parking structure.
我想问一下 这道楼梯是不是直通电梯?
Let me ask you... Does this stairway go up to the escalator?
- 对 - 告诉他们继续
- Yeah. - Tell them to go ahead.
你们要干什么?
What's going on?
你看呢?我们要冲进去
What's it look like? We're going in.
冲进去!你疯了吗? 上面可能有30名人质
Going in? That's crazy! There could be over 30 hostages in there for all we know.
我们什么也不知道 鲍尔
We don't know shit, Powell.
如果有人质 为什么不提出赎金的数目?
If there's hostages, how come there are no ransom demands?
如果有恐怖分子 他们为什么不提出要求?
If there's terrorists in there, where's their list of demands?
我们只知道 有人向你的车开枪
All we know is that somebody shot your car up.
说不定就是
It's probably the same silly son of a bitch
刚才和你通话的蠢货
you've been talking to on that radio.
对不起 长官!
Excuse me, sir,
那具从天而降的屍体 又怎么解释?
but what about the body that fell out the window?
- 也许是破产的股票经纪人 - 我们准备好了 局长
- Maybe a stockbroker got depressed. - We're ready.
- 好吧 把灯打开 行动 - 把灯打开
- Light 'em up. Let's go. - Hit your lights.
- 蓝队行动 - 开灯
- Blue units, go. - Lights on!
鲍尔?
Powell?
艾尔 你还在吗 伙计? 这是怎么了?
Powell, you still with me, babe? What's goin' on?
嘿 艾尔?
Yo, Al.
我在这儿 罗伊 不过我现在很忙 过会儿再说
I'm here, Roy, but I'm busy right now. I'll talk to you later.
艾尔 怎么回事?
Al, what's wrong?
我说了过会儿再说
I'll talk to you later.
如果你是我想的那样
If you are what I think you are,
那么你该知道 何时该听 何时闭嘴…
you'll know when to listen, shut up, and...
何时该祈祷
and when to pray.
我的天 你们想冲进来! 是不是?
Jesus Christ! You're coming in, right?
我跟你说过 这些家伙不是好惹的
I told you what kind of people you're dealing with!
作好准备
Let's load them up.
哦 他们来了 大家准备好
They'll be coming. Everyone get ready.
西奥 你负责监视
Theo, you are the eyes now.
雷沃!
Rivers.
开始侦察行动
Begin your reconnoiter.
我们走!
Let's go.
妈的!
Shit!
快点!上吧!
Come on. Let's go.
哦 该死
Jesus!
大家散开
All right, spread out.
(卸货区)
闭嘴
Shut up.
上!
Let's go.
你们这些鲁莽的笨蛋 不!不!
You macho assholes. No! No!
好啦 大夥听着
All right. Listen up, guys.
圣诞前夕
'Twas the night before Christmas
万籁俱寂
and all through the house
屋内一片平静，除了…
not a creature was stirring, except
四个家伙想从後面进来
the four assholes coming in the rear in standard
标准两两掩护队形
two-by-two cover formation.
好啦 我们已经到位
We're all set.
准备好了
We're ready.
干吧
Kick ass.
上!
Go!
好 行动
Right. Let's do it.
遭受攻击!
Take cover!
他们朝蓝队开枪!
They're shooting at 'em.
- 乱开枪 他们什么也看不见 - 他们在射探照灯
- It's panic fire. They can't see anything. - They're shooting at the lights.
他们的目标是探照灯 叫他们回来
They're going after the lights. Call 'em back.
这锁打不开
It's not happening.
麦克 烧开它!
Mike, burn it.
沉住气
Don't be impatient.
打伤就可以了
Just wound them.
让他们回来! 没有灯光他们都是靶子
Get them back. They're sitting ducks.
不 他们就要进去了
They're almost in.
让装甲车过来
Send in the car.
我的天!
Jesus Christ!
雷沃!罗德里格斯! 回话
Rivers, Rodriguez, report.
等一下 猜猜是谁来了?
Wait a minute. What have we here, gentlemen?
警方派来一辆大玩具
The police have themselves an RV.
东南角
Southeast corner.
哦 上帝
Oh, Jesus Christ.
走开!退後!
Get back! Get the fuck back!
快到那边去
Get over there.
我看见他了!
I see him!
哦 我的天! 四分卫完蛋了!
Oh, my God! The quarterback is toast!
撑着 雷沃! 这是命令!
Hang on, Rivers. That's an order.
再来一次
Hit it again.
汉斯 你这个王八蛋! 你成功了 让他们走!
All right, you made your point! Let them pull back!
谢谢 牛仔先生 我会考虑你的意见，但…
Thank you. I'll take it under advisement.
再来
Hit it
一次
again.
发射
Fire.
妈的
Fuck me.
把他们救出来! 他们就要被烧死了!
Get them out of the car! They're burning!
去你的
Fuck it.
这个意见你接不接受 蠢货
Let's see you take this under advisement, jerkweed.
去死吧 王八蛋!
Geronimo, motherfucker.
天哪!
Oh, shit!
他们用大炮打我们!
They're using artillery!
蠢货 不是警方干的
You idiot, it's not the police.
是他
It's him.
我的天!
Holy shit.
天哪!
My God!
- 告诉我你拍到了 - 拍到了
- Tell me you got that. - I got it.
最佳镜头 第五频道
Eat your heart out, Channel 5.
占据中富大厦的恐怖分子 我们有最新了解
We've had an update on the terrorist takeover of the Nakatomi building.
有消息称他们的领导 汉斯
Sources say the terrorist leader, Hans,
也许就是汉斯·格鲁伯
may be this man... Hans Gruber.
激进的西德人民阵线组织成员
A member of the radical West German Volksfrei movement.
奇怪的是 人民阵线领导人一小时前
Strangely, the Volksfrei leadership issued a communique an hour ago
声称格鲁伯 已被逐出该组织
stating that Gruber had been expelled from that organization.
艾尔?听到了吗?
Al, do you copy?
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
对 我很好
Yeah, I'm fine.
刚才怎么回事?
What was that?
还记得我说过的塑胶炸药吗?
Remember that plastic explosive I told you about?
- 记得 - 就是它 大厦起火了吗?
- Yeah. - There you go. Is the building on fire?
没有 不过需要重新刷漆
No, but it's gonna need a paintjob
还要换许多玻璃门
and a shitload of screen doors.
观察哨说 爆炸干掉两个
Our spotter said you got two with that blast.
- 是他吗? - 是 长官
- Is that him? - Yes, sir.
现在你听好了 先生 我不知道你想干嘛
I don't know who you think you are
但是你毁了一座大厦!
but you just destroyed a building.
我们不需要你的帮助 明白了吗?
We do not want your help. Is that clear?
我们不需要你的帮助
We don't want your help.
下面有一百多人 被碎玻璃活埋啦
I've got 100 people down here covered with glass.
玻璃?谁还管他妈的玻璃?
Glass? Who gives a shit about glass?
你他妈的是谁?
Who the fuck is this?
我是副局长杜恩·罗宾森
This is Deputy Chief of Police Dwayne T Robinson
这里我说了算
and I am in charge of this situation.
哦 你说了算?
Oh, you're in charge?
有些坏消息要告诉你 杜恩
I got some bad news for you, Dwayne.
从我这看 你他妈的屁也管不了
From up here it doesn't look like you're in charge of shit.
你给我听着 你这个白痴
Listen to me, you little asshole...
白痴?
Asshole?
在电视上丢脸的
I'm not the one who just got buttfucked
可不是我 杜恩!
on national TV, Dwayne.
你给我听着 蠢货
Listen to me, jerk-off,
如果你没有办法 就别在这儿捣乱
if you're not part of the solution, you're part of the problem.
把对讲机还给刚才的那个人
Quit being part of the problem and put the other guy back on!
嘿 罗伊 感觉怎么样?
Hey, Roy, how you feeling?
我感到很不得志 艾尔
Pretty fucking unappreciated, Al.
嘿 听着 我喜欢你
Hey, look. I love you.
很多人都喜欢你
So do a lot of the other guys.
你一定要坚持住 听到了吗?
So hang in there, man, you hear me?
你要坚持住
You hang in there.
明白 谢谢 伙计
Yeah, thanks, partner.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
我不想坐在这儿 看谁先把我们杀死
I'm tired of sitting here waiting to see who gets us killed first,
他们还是你丈夫
them or your husband.
你到底想干什么?
What are you going to do?
我一顿饭就能谈下百万美元 难道连这些人渣都对付不了?
I negotiate million-dollar deals for breakfast. I think I can handle this Eurotrash.
嘿 谈谈怎么样 嗯?
Hey, sprechen sie talk, huh?
要是听我的 他早就被困住了
If you'd listened to me, he would be neutralized already.
我不想困住他 我要他死
I don't want neutral. I want dead.
我没有打搅你们吧?
Hope I'm not interrupting.
他想要什么?
What does he want?
不是我想要什么 而是我能给你们什么
It's not what I want. It's what I can give you.
听着 我还是直说了吧
Look, let's be straight, OK?
很明显 你们到这来不只是 为了偷几个小钱 对吗?
It's obvious you're not some dumb schmuck up here to snatch a few purses.
你很会观察
You're very perceptive.
啊 我有在看“六十分钟”
I watch 60 Minutes.
我对自己说:“这些人都是行家
I say to myself, these guys are professional,
他们有动机、他们有计划”
they're motivated, they're happening,
总之 他们想要什么东西
they want something.
我个人并不关心 你们的政治信仰
I couldn't care less about your politics.
也许你们对阿拉伯人不满
Maybe you're pissed off at the camel jockeys.
也许是以色列或是北爱 这不关我的事
Maybe it's Northern Ireland. It's none of my business.
你们是来谈判的 不错吧?
I figure you're here to negotiate, am I right?
令人惊讶
You're amazing.
全部是你自己想出来的?
You figured this all out already?
嘿 生意就是生意
Hey, business is business.
你们用枪 我用笔 有什么区别?
You use a gun, I use a fountain pen. What's the difference?
我这样说吧 你们的目的是钱
In my terms, you're here on a hostile takeover.
你计划好一切 但没想到有一颗老鼠屎坏事
You grab us for some greenmail but didn't expect a poison pill to be running around.
对吗?
Am I right?
汉斯
Hans,
老弟
bubbee,
我就是你的白骑士
I'm your white knight.
我没看过“六十分钟”
I must have missed "60 Minutes".
你是什么意思?
What are you saying?
楼上那家伙坏了你们的事 嗯?
The guy upstairs who's fucking things up, huh?
我可以把他交给你
I can give him to you.
哦 妈的!
Oh, God...
罗伊! 罗伊 你还好吗?
Roy? Roy, you all right?
这些饼乾比我还老
Just trying to fire down a 1,000-year-old Twinkie.
它是什么东西做的?
What do they put in them?
高糖面粉、氢化植物油…
Sugar-enriched flour, partially hydrogenated vegetable oil,
聚山梨醇酯60
polysorbate 60,
五号黄色色素
and yellow dye number five.
孩子发育需要的一切营养
Just everything a growing boy needs.
你有多少个孩子 艾尔?
How many kids you got, Al?
事实上 我的妻子正怀第一个
As a matter of fact, my wife is working on our first.
你呢 牛仔?
How about you, cowboy?
你的农场里有孩子吗?
You got any kids back on your ranch?
有
Yeah.
两个
Two.
希望他们以後 能和你儿子一起荡秋千
Sure hope I can see them swinging on ajungle gym with Al Jnr someday.
那就说定了
Well, now, that's a date
不过你可要带冰淇淋来
but you bring the ice cream.
感人 牛仔 非常感人
Touching, cowboy. Touching.
也许我该叫你
Or should I call you
麦克连先生?
Mr McClane?
纽约警察局的
Mr Officer John McClane
约翰·麦克连警官
of the New York Police Department?
给纽约的哈里打电话
Get on the phone to Harry in New York.
你让指挥中心的人查一查
You better get hold of somebody at Dispatch.
德蕾莎修女在三年级时 叫我麦克连先生
Sister Theresa called me Mr McClane in the third grade.
我的朋友们叫我约翰 你谁也不是 人渣
My friends call me John... and you're neither, shithead.
这有个人想和你谈谈 一位特殊的朋友
I have someone who wants to talk to you. A very special friend
晚会上和你在一起的
who was with you at the party tonight.
嘿 约翰兄
Hey, John boy.
艾利斯?
Ellis?
对
Yeah.
现在听着 约翰 他们给我几分钟让我跟你说话
Listen, John, they're giving me a few minutes to talk sense into you.
我知道你认为自己在尽职
I know you think you're doing yourjob
我表示感谢 但你让情况变得复杂
but you're just dragging this out. No one gets out of here until these guys
让这些人和洛杉矶警察谈判
can talk to the LA police.
你必须停止捣乱 否则谁也甭想出去 明白吗?
That won't happen until you stop messing up the works.
艾利斯 你对他们说过什么?
Ellis, what have you told them?
我说我们是老朋友 而今天晚上…
I told them we were old friends and you were my guest
你是我的客人
at the party.
艾利斯 你不该这么做
Ellis, you shouldn't be doin' this.
这个不用你说?
Tell me about it.
好了 约翰 听着
All right, John, listen.
他们想让你说出雷管的下落
Tell them where the detonators are.
他们知道有人在听
They know people are listening.
他们需要雷管 否则他们会杀了我
They want the detonators, or they're gonna kill me.
约翰 你听见了吗?
John, didn't you hear me?
对 我听见了
Yeah, I hear you.
嘿 约翰 我想你还是别管闲事了 嗯? 警察已经到了 这是他们的事
John, get with the program! The police are here now. It's their problem.
告诉他们雷管在哪儿 就没有人会受伤!
Tell them where the detonators are!
知道吗 我是在为你赌命 老兄
I'm putting my life on the line for you, pal!
艾利斯 你仔细地听我说
Ellis, listen to me carefully.
约翰…
John...
闭嘴 艾利斯!马上给我闭嘴!
Shut up, Ellis! Just shut your mouth!
把对讲机交给汉斯
Put Hans back on.
汉斯 这个蠢货不了解情况 但我知道 听着
Hans, this shithead does not know what kind of man you are but I do.
很好 那就交出雷管 拯救你朋友的生命
Then you'll give us what we want and save your friend's life.
这件事与你毫无关系
You're not part of this equation.
嘿 那我呢?
Hey, what am I, a method actor?
老兄 把枪拿开 这是对讲机 不是电视
Babe, put away the gun. This is radio, not television.
汉斯 这个混蛋不是我朋友! 我们刚碰面 我根本不认识他
Hans, this asshole is not my friend! I don't know him!
艾利斯 这些人会杀了你! 告诉他们你不认识我!
Jesus Christ, Ellis! These people will kill you! Tell them you don't know me!
这么多年的交情 怎么能这么说?
How can you say that after all these years?
约翰?约翰?
John? John?
你听见啦?
Do you hear that?
告诉我 我的雷管在哪儿?
Talk to me! Where are my detonators?
说出来 否则我就再杀一个
Where are they, or shall I shoot another one?
迟早会轮到 那个你真正关心的人
Sooner or later, I might get to someone you do care about.
去你妈的 汉斯
Go fuck yourself, Hans.
听到吗 是他害死了那个人
He just let the guy die.
他不管他的死活 把对讲机给我
He gave him up. Give me that headset.
这和亲手扣扳机没什么两样
That's like pulling the trigger yourself.
难道你不知道是怎么回事吗? 难道你看不出来吗?
Can't you see what's happening? Can't you read between the lines?
他尽了一切努力去救他!
He did everything he could to save him.
如果他投降 那么他俩都已经死了!
If he gave himself up, they'd both be dead right now!
不行 不行 他们要和我们谈判
No way, man. They'd be talking to us.
听着 告诉你那位夥伴 从现在开始别再插手 你听见了吗?
You tell this partner of yours to stay out of this from now on.
要是他不听 我就要他好看 听着 我会给他好看的
Because if he doesn't, I'm really going to nail his ass.
他已经受伤 孤单又疲惫
The man is hurting. He is alone, tired,
下面的这些人却无所事事
and he hasn't seen diddly-squat from anybody here!
现在你却站在这儿告诉我
You're gonna tell me he'll give a damn
就算他能活着出来 你也要给他好看?
about what you do to him if he makes it out of there alive?
好好想想自己说的这些屁话
Why don't you wake up and smell what you shovelin'?
你给我听着 警官
You listen to me, sergeant.
你要是想回家 随时可以辞职
Any time you want to go home, you consider yourself dismissed.
不 长官 你甭想赶我走!
No, sir. You couldn't drag me away.
警方注意
Attention, police.
- 我是艾尔·鲍尔警官 - 把它给我
- This is Sergeant Al Powell... - Give me that.
这是、这是副局长 杜恩·罗宾森
This is Deputy Chief Dwayne Robinson.
你是谁?
Who is this?
我是汉斯·格鲁伯
This is Hans Gruber.
我想你们 已经知道进攻我们的直接後果
I assume you realize the futility of direct action against me.
我们不想再有人丧命
We have no wish for further loss of life.
你到底想要什么 格鲁伯先生?
What is it you do wish for?
我的同志 正在世界各地受牢狱之苦
I have comrades in arms around the world languishing in prison.
美国政府不是 喜欢到处炫耀武力吗?
The American State Department enjoys rattling its saber for its own ends.
现在为我炫耀一回吧
Now it can rattle it for me.
以下这些人必须被立即释放
The following people are to be released from their captors.
北爱尔兰扣押的 七名爱尔兰共和军成员
In Northern Ireland the seven members of the New Provo Front.
加拿大扣押的五名 魁北克解放运动领导人
In Canada, the five imprisoned leaders of Liberte de Quebec.
斯里兰卡扣押的 九名亚洲曙光运动组织成员
In Sri Lanka, the nine members of the Asian Dawn.
搞什么鬼?
What the fuck?
亚洲曙光运动?
Asian Dawn?
我在《时代》杂志上看到的
I read about them in Time magazine.
这些革命的兄弟姐妹 重获自由以後
When these revolutionary brothers and sisters are free,
这里的人质将被押到大厦楼顶
the hostages in this building will be taken to the roof
他们将和我们一起乘直升机 到达洛杉矶国际机场
and they will accompany us in helicopters to the Los Angeles International Airport
到那里後 我再告诉你下一步该怎么做
where they will be given further instructions.
你们有两个小时的时间
You have two hours to comply.
等等 稍等一下 格鲁伯先生
Wait a minute. Mr. Gruber. This is crazy.
我、我、我没有这个权力 两个小时根本不够
I don't have the authority. Two hours is not enough.
喂 哈罗?哈罗?
Hello? Hello!
你都录下来了吗? 我们去打几个电话
Did you get all that? We got to make some calls.
你以为他们会照办吗?
Do you think they'll even try?
管他呢?
Who cares?
西奥 进展如何?
Theo, are we on schedule?
还有一道锁 然後就看你的了
One more to go, then it's up to you.
最好你是对的 要打开最後一道 只能靠奇蹟了
You better be right, because the last one will take a miracle.
今天是圣诞节 西奥
It's Christmas, Theo.
是奇蹟的节日 保持愉快的心情
It's the time of miracles, so be of good cheer
解最後一道锁的时候再告诉我
and call me when you hit the last lock.
卡尔
Karl,
干掉那个小混蛋 把雷管夺回来
hunt that little shit down and get those detonators.
佛里正在检查炸药
Fritz is checking the explosives.
我去检查炸药 你只管夺回雷管
I'll check the explosives. You get the detonators.
嘿 伙计 你还在吗?
Hey, Powell, you out there?
我在这儿 约翰 我在这儿
I'm here, John. I'm here.
你必须相信我 我已经无能为力了
You gotta believe me. There was nothing I could do.
要是你错了 我们俩都得倒霉
Well, it's gonna be both our asses if you're wrong.
我明白
I hear you.
你听见汉斯的那套鬼话了吗?
Did you catch that bullshit Hans was running?
不太对头 伙计
It doesn't make sense, man.
嘿 不要问我 我只是一个 在你求救时正想回家的警察
Don't ask me. I'm just a deskjockey who was on my way home when you rang.
看你开车的样子 还以为你是个巡警
The way you drove that car, I figured you for the street, Al.
我年轻的时候曾经是
In my youth. In my youth.
人质与恐怖分子双向研究
...author of "Hostage Terrorist, Terrorist Hostage:
的作者海瑟多夫博士
A Study in Duality."
海瑟多夫博士 你预期 接下来的几小时会怎么样?
Dr Hasseldorf, what can we expect in the next few hours?
哦 盖儿 在这个时候…
Well, Gail,
人质将经历
by this time, the hostages should be going through
赫尔辛基症候群的早期阶段
the early stages of the Helsinki Syndrome.
就是瑞典的赫尔辛基
As in Helsinki, Sweden.
是芬兰
Finland.
基本上 人质与恐怖分子
Basically, it's when the hostages and the terrorists
将经历某种心理转移
go through a sort of psychological transference
并产生彼此依赖的感觉
and a projection of dependency.
发展出某种奇怪的信任与友情
A strange sort of trust and bond develops.
在某些案例中 人质在获释後…
We've had situations where the hostages
会拥抱绑架者
have embraced their captors after release
甚至和狱中的他们通信
and even corresponded with them in prison.
不 宝贝 是亚洲曙光
No, no, darling. Asian Dawn. Dawn.
是曙光
D-A-W-N.
- 长官? - 什么?
- Sir? - Yeah?
联邦调查局的人来了
Sir, the FBI is here.
- 他们来了? - 对 长官 就在那边
- The FBI is here now? - Yes, sir. Right over there.
拿着
Hold this.
不来点口香糖吗?
Want a breath mint?
嘿 你还好吗 伙计?
Hey, how you doing, man?
我是探员强森 这位是特别探员强森
I'm Agent Johnson. This is Special Agent Johnson.
- 哦 你们好吗? - 不是亲戚
- Oh, how you doing? - No relation.
我是杜恩.罗宾森 洛杉矶警察局的 负责这里
I'm Dwayne Robinson, LAPD. I'm in charge here.
不再是了
Not anymore.
嗨 伙计 你好啊?
Hi, there. How you doin'?
天啊! 你是他们一夥的 对吗?
Please, God. No. You're one of them, aren't you?
你是他们一夥的
You're one of them.
哦 别杀我 求求你!
No! Don't kill me! Please!
别杀我!求求你!
Don't kill me, please! Please, please, please.
放松!我不会伤害你
Whoa. Relax. I'm not gonna hurt you.
我不会伤害你!
I'm not gonna hurt you!
哦 我的天
Oh, God.
你在这上面干什么? 你在找什么?
What the fuck are you doin' up here? What were you lookin' for?
我设法逃了出来 我…
I managed to get out of there and
我想逃到楼顶
I was just trying to get up on the roof
看看能否发出求救信号
and see if I could signal for help.
就从这边走 你可以过来帮我…
It's through here. Come and help.
停下 不能去楼顶
Hold it. Forget the roof.
我说了 不能去楼顶 到处都是他们的人
I said forget the roof. They got people all over it.
你要是想活命 就和我在一起
You wanna stay alive, you stay with me.
我们现在只知道
The best we can figure it,
也许在第30层有大约
we've got maybe 30 or 35 hostages up there,
30到35名人质
probably on the 30th floor,
和大概七八个匪徒
and maybe seven or eight terrorists up there.
听起来好像是A-7状况
Sounds like an A-7 scenario.
谢谢 从现在开始由我们接管
Thank you. We'll handle it from here.
需要用你的人时 我会通知你的
When we commandeer your men, we'll try and let you know.
你是不是忘了点什么?
Aren't you forgetting something?
什么?
Such as?
约翰·麦克连呢?
What about John McClane?
有他 才有我们刚才那些资料
He's the reason we have any information.
有他 你们要对付的只剩七个 而不是十二个匪徒
He's also the reason you're facing seven terrorists, not twelve.
他在里面?他是谁?
He's inside? Who is he?
他也许是个警察 我们正在核实
He might be a cop. We're checking on that.
- 是你的人? - 不 绝对不是
- One of yours? - No, no way.
你抽菸吗?
You smoke?
对
Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
你不是中富公司的
You don't work for Nakatomi.
你也不是恐怖分子
And if you're not one of them...
我是纽约警察
I'm a cop from New York.
纽约?
New York?
对
Yeah.
阴差阳错来参加这个晚会
Got invited to the Christmas party by mistake.
没想到
Who knew?
总比光着屁股被抓到好 嗯?
Better than being caught with your pants down, huh?
我叫约翰·麦克连
I'm John McClane.
你是…
You're?
克雷
Clay.
比尔·克雷
Bill Clay.
知道怎么用手枪吗 比尔?
Know how to use a handgun, Bill?
我曾在野战营过了一星期
I spent a weekend at a combat ranch.
你知道那种 发射红色颜料球的枪吗?
That game with the guns that shoot red paint.
也许对你来说有点傻
Probably seems kind of stupid to you.
不
Nope.
要动真格的了 比尔
Time for the real thing, Bill.
扣下扳机就对了
All you gotta do is pull the trigger.
走吧
Come on.
把枪放下 把雷管还给我
Put down the gun and give me my detonators.
看看是谁
Well, well, well...
汉斯
Hans.
把枪放下 马上
Put it down now.
装出那种口音的确不简单
That's pretty tricky with that accent.
你应该上电视表演
You oughta be on fucking TV with that accent.
你要这些雷管想干什么?
But what do you want with the detonators?
我已经用光了所有炸药
I already used all the explosives.
是吗?
Or did I?
我只数到三
I'm going to count to three.
对了 就像对高木那样?
Yeah. Like you did with Takagi?
没有子弹
No bullets.
你以为我很蠢吗 汉斯?
What do you think... I'm fuckin' stupid, Hans?
你说呢?
You were saying?
打碎玻璃
Shoot the glass!
王八蛋!
Jesus Christ!
笑吧 卡尔 我们又开张了
Smile, Karl. We're back in business.
…是外交的最後手段
...is the last resort of diplomacy,
我们或许可以这么说
then couldn't we just as well say
恐怖主义也有同样的效果
that terrorism has an equal claim on being that, too?
告诉我你找到什么了?
Tell me you got something.
只有麦克连的名字、警徽号 任职记录、基本数据
McClane's name, badge number, employment record, vital statistics,
和他家人的地址
and his family's home address
就在洛杉矶这里
right here in LA.
去工作
Go to work.
明白
Got it.
天哪 那个人好像真的很生气
God, that man looks really pissed.
他还活着
He's still alive.
什么?
What?
只有约翰才能把人逼成那样
Only John can drive somebody that crazy.
汉斯 快带你的奇蹟来 我们刚打开第六道
Hans, heat up that miracle because we just broke through on number six
电磁密封突然就启动了
and the electromagnetic came down like an anvil.
很好 先看看窗外的朋友 在干什么 我马上就到
Have a look at what our friends outside are doing and I'll be right up.
嘿 约翰
Hey, John.
约翰·麦克连 你还在吗?
John McClane, you still with us?
在
Yeah.
不过要是让我选 我宁愿到费城去
But all things being equal, I'd rather be in Philadelphia.
又干掉两个坏蛋
Chalk up two more bad guys.
很高兴听到这消息
The boys down here will be glad to hear that.
知道吗 我们都在你身上下了注
We got a pool going on you.
我现在的赔率是多少?
What kind of odds am I getting?
你最好别知道
You don't want to know.
帮我下20块
Put me down for 20.
我赔得起
I'm good for it.
嘿 鲍尔 你是平足吗?
Hey, pal, you got flat feet?
你这是什么意思 伙计?
What the hell you talking about, man?
你为什么不干巡警了?
Something had to get you off the street.
这有什么?
What's the matter?
你认为在办公桌後面 整理文件就不是警察了吗?
You don't think a desk job is a noble effort for a cop?
不
No.
我出过一次意外
I had an accident.
像你那样开车肯定得出事
The way you drive, I can see why.
是什么事故?
What'd you do?
开车轧了队长的脚吗?
Run over your captain's foot with the car?
我杀了一个孩子
I shot a kid.
他当时只有13岁
He was 13 years old.
天很黑 我看不清楚 他拿着逼真的玩具枪
Oh, it was dark. I couldn't see him. He had a ray gun, looked real enough.
警察学校 把你从菜鸟教成老手
When you're a rookie, they teach you everything about being a cop
却没教你怎么背下责任
except how to live with a mistake.
总之 我再也无法 用枪指着任何人了
Anyway, I just couldn't bring myself to draw my gun on anybody again.
抱歉 伙计
Sorry, man.
嘿 伙计 你能体会吗?
Hey, man, how could you know?
我现在感觉很糟
I feel like shit anyway.
那我还是告诉你吧
Well, this won't matter.
现在不是洛杉矶警察掌舵了
DoThe LAPD is not calling the shots down here anymore.
调查局?
The Feds?
你说对了
You got it.
你看 这些是市政工程师
Those are the city engineers.
等等
Wait.
他们在查看街道电路
They're going into the street circuits.
看那些穿西装的家伙 不知是干什么的
The guys in suits, I don't know who they are.
那就是调查局的
That's the FBI.
他们依照程序 下令切断大厦的电源
They're ordering the others to cut the building's power.
像发条一样规律
Regular as clockwork.
就像一把钥匙
Or a time lock.
正确
Precisely.
为了对抗一起恐怖活动…
The circuits that cannot be cut are cut automatically
无法切断的电路 於是被迫切断了
in response to a terrorist incident.
想要奇蹟 西奥 就去找…
You asked for miracles, Theo.
联邦调查局
I give you the F-B-I.
我要你切断这座大厦的电源!
I want the building shut down.
嘿 我这儿有点问题
I got a problem. I got a switch...
我不管你有什么样的问题! 必须关闭这个开关
I don't care about your switch. I want it out. Dark!
不能从这儿切断
You can't do it from here.
- 可以 - 不能从这儿切断!
- Yeah, you could. - It can't be done from here.
我们可以…我有对讲机
I could... I got the radio...
不能从这儿切断电源 只能从市中心切断
You can't do it from here. It's got to be done from downtown.
整个电网都会断电 这关系到十个街区
They've gotta take out a whole city grid. We're talking 10 square blocks.
十个街区? 天哪 强森 你疯了吗?
Ten blocks? Johnson, that's crazy.
今天是圣诞夜 成千上万的人…
It's Christmas Eve. There's thousands of people.
我们必须这样做!
You have to go wider.
- 我需要授权! - 美国政府授权还不够吗?
- I need authorization. - How about the United States government?
切断电网 要么丢掉饭碗
Lose the grid, or you lose yourjob.
中心吗?
Yeah, Central?
我是沃尔特 在中富大厦
This is Walt, down at Nakatomi.
听着 你帮我切断212电网好吗?
Would it be possible for you to turn off grid 212?
你疯了吗?
Are you crazy?!
也许我该给市长打个电话
Maybe I should call the mayor.
倒霉的是我 我这儿麻烦大了 快关掉
No shit it's my ass. I got a big problem here.
切断电源 马上!
Shut it down now.
启动紧急电源
Emergency lighting activated.
鲍尔!回答我 这是怎么回事?
Al, talk to me. What's going on here?
去问调查局吧
Ask the FBI.
他们正拿着反恐怖指南
They got the universal terrorist playbook
按部就班地照办
and they're running it step by step.
要打开了 要开了!
It's gonna go. It's gonna go!
好的！
Yes!
圣诞快乐!
Merry Christmas.
那帮杂种可能已经尿了裤子了
They must be pissing in their pants.
市长会杀了我
The mayor is gonna have my ass.
现在我们该怎么办?
What are we gonna do now?
因为拒付电费逮捕他们吗?
Arrest them for not paying their electric bill?
把他们关在里面
We've shut them down.
让他们流点冷汗 然後给他们直昇机
We let them sweat for a while, then we give them helicopters.
一个不留
Right up the ass.
我是强森探员
This is Agent Johnson.
不 是另一个
No, the other one.
我需要空中支援在五分钟内出发
I want that air support ready to lift off in five minutes.
没错 全副武装 我们马上就到
Damn right. Fully armed. We're on the way.
耶!
Oh, yes!
我要和联邦调查局的人谈
I wish to talk to the FBI.
我是特别探员强森
This is Special Agent Johnson.
州政府已经安排你的同志们回家了
The State Department has arranged for the return of your comrades.
直昇机马上就到 按照你的要求
Helicopters are en route as you requested.
我知道了 我们正在准备
I hear you. We'll be ready.
等他知道上当的时候 已经在屍袋里了
When he figures out what hit him, he'll be in a body bag.
他们一着陆 我们就炸了楼顶
When they touch down, we'll blow the roof.
等他们查出原因 我们已经在海滩上吃红利了
By the time they figure it all out, we'll be sitting on a beach earning 20%.
哦 妈的!
Ah! Jeez!
鲍尔?
Powell?
嘿 鲍尔 你有空吗?
Yo, Powell, you got a minute?
我在这儿 约翰
I'm here, John.
听着 伙计 我现在有一种 不祥的感觉
Listen, I'm starting to get a bad feeling up here.
我想请你帮我一个忙
I want you to do something for me.
嗯…请你去找我的妻子 别问我怎么找 到时候你会知道的
I want you to find my wife. Don't ask me how. By then you'll know how.
请你帮我转告她 我想请你告诉她…
I want you to tell her something. I want you to tell her that...
告诉她我现在才知道
Tell her it took me a while to figure out
我真是个混蛋
what ajerk I've been
不过
but...
在她…
that...
在她获得大好机会的时候
that when things started to pan out for her
我本应该去支持她
I shoulda... been more supportive.
而且…
And...
让她无後顾之忧
I just should have been behind her more.
哦 妈的
Oh, shit.
你告诉她
Tell her that...
对我这样的流浪汉 她简直就是一种恩赐
that she's the best thing that ever happened to a bum like me.
她曾听我说过一千遍“我爱你”
She's heard me say "I love you" a thousand times.
却从未听我说“对不起”
She never heard me say "I'm sorry".
我希望你帮我告诉她 约翰说对不起
I want you to tell her that, Al. Tell her that John said that he was sorry.
好吗?
OK?
你听见了吗?
You got that, man?
是 我听见了 约翰
Yeah, I got it, John.
你可以自己去跟她说
But you can tell her that yourself.
只要你小心 肯定能活着出来 你明白吗?
You just watch your ass and you'll make it out. You hear me?
哦 我想这得问问楼上的人
I guess that's up to the man upstairs.
约翰?
John?
你在楼上搞什么鬼 汉斯?
What the fuck were you doing upstairs, Hans?
约翰!
John?
哦 艾尔 听着 过会儿再和你聊
No, Al, listen. Just lay off for a while.
我现在得去查看一下
I gotta go check on something.
一分钟!我只要一分钟
One minute, that's all I'm asking.
我只和他们谈一分钟
One minute to speak to them.
好吧 不许生人进来
All right. Get back. Get back.
好吧 退後 走!走!
All right, look.
听着 你让我进去 否则我就找移民局
You let me in right now, or I call the INS, comprende?
这也许是孩子们最後一次 和他们的父母说话
This is the last time these kids are gonna have to speak to their parents.
好吗?
All right?
好啦 过来
All right. Come on. Come on.
你在干什么 汉斯?
What were you doin', Hans?
你在干什么?
What were you doin'?
天啊 圣母玛丽亚
Jesus, Mary, mother of God.
鲍尔 鲍尔! 听我说!
Al, listen to me! It's a double cross!
这是圈套! 整个大厦的顶层全是…
The roof is wired to...
约翰?
John?
John!
约翰 回话!
John, come in!
你听到了吗?
Did you get that?
好像是什么圈套
Something about a double cross.
这还用你说
Tell me about it.
我们都是高手
We are both professionals.
这是私人恩怨
This is personal.
他们来了
They're comin'!
直昇机来了
Choppers are comin'.
把你的人集中起来 吉奈萝小姐
Time to gather your flock, Miss Gennero.
你的爸爸妈妈非常重要
Your mom and dad are very important people.
他们很勇敢
They're very brave people.
你有什么话要告诉他们吗? 他们正看着呢
Is there something you'd like to say to them, if they're watching?
回家吧
Come home.
麦克连太太
Mrs McClane.
很高兴和您见面
How nice to make your acquaintance.
都给我站起来!到楼顶去!
On your feet, everyone! To the roof!
把他们锁在那儿然後回来!
Lock them up there and come right back.
你应该听听你兄弟的惨叫! 当我拧断他脖子的时候!
You should have heard your brother squeal... when I broke his fucking neck!
你估计会有多少损失?
What do you figure the breakage?
我们干掉恐怖分子 会损失20%到25%的人质
I figure we take out the terrorists, lose 20, 25% of the hostages, tops.
这个可以接受
I can live with that.
把机枪藏在飞机里面
Get this thing on the deck.
要伪装成运输机 而不是攻击机
They're expecting transports, not gun ships.
快点!跟上!快点!
Move it! Come on! Move!
快!快走!
Come on! Come on!
快一点!
Move it!
快走!快一点!
Go! Move!
西奥
Theo.
我们的红利
A little bonus for us.
请你坐下
Please, sit down. Sit down!
一个警察的妻子也许有点用
A policeman's wife might come in handy.
麦克连 我有个消息告诉你
McClane, I have some news for you.
麦克连?
McClane?
快走!跟上!
Move!
快走!
Come on!
王八蛋!我要杀了你!
Motherfucker! I'll kill you!
好了
Armed.
- 我去开车? - 去开车
- The truck? - The truck.
摆了那么多姿态 说了那么多废话
After all your posturing, all your little speeches,
你也不过就是个小贼
you're nothing but a common thief.
我不是寻常的贼 麦克连太太
I am an exceptional thief, Mrs McClane.
既然我现在是绑架者 就请你礼貌一点!
And since I'm moving up to kidnapping, you should be more polite.
王八蛋!我要杀了你!
You motherfucker, I'm gonna kill you!
我要煮了你 然後再吃掉!
I'm gonna fuckin' cook you, and I'm gonna fuckin' eat you!
我不喜欢这样
I don't like this.
就像他妈的西贡 嘿 小子?
Just like fucking Saigon, eh, Slick?
当时我在念初中 笨蛋
I was in junior high, dickhead.
荷莉在哪儿?
Where's Holly?
荷莉·吉奈萝在哪儿?
Where's Holly Gennero?
荷莉·吉奈萝! 荷莉在哪儿?
Holly Gennero? Where's Holly?
荷莉在哪儿?她在哪儿?
Where's Holly? Where is she?
- 她被抓走了! - 在哪儿?
- They took her! - Where?
在金库!
The vault!
- 金库在哪儿? - 在第30层!
- Where is the vault? - The 30th floor!
楼梯上面 她被抓走了
They just took her!
到楼下去!
Get downstairs!
这个楼顶就要爆炸啦!快下去!
The whole fucking roof is wired to blow! Get down!
快下去!快他妈的下去!
Get down! Get the fuck downstairs!
他们发现了 探员们 一名恐怖分子在射击
They made us, Bureau. You got a terrorist shooting hostages.
我看到了!向左飞
I see him! Break left!
我看见了 杀了那个混蛋!
Nail that sucker!
我是你们一夥的 混蛋!
I'm on your side, you assholes!
妈的!再转回去! 我要收拾这个杂种!
Swing around again! I'll bag this little bastard.
哦 你他妈的…
What the fuck...
哦 约翰 你他妈的到这来干什么?
Oh, John, what the fuck are you doin'?
你他妈的怎么这么倒霉?
How the fuck did you get into this shit?
有点不对头!他们又回来了!
There's somethin' wrong! They're comin' back down!
- 炸掉屋顶 - 可卡尔还在上面!
- Blow the roof. - But Karl's up there!
炸掉屋顶!
Blow the roof!
我发誓 我以後再也不想…
I promise I will never even think
登上任何高楼大厦
about going up in a tall building again.
哦 天啊 千万别让我死!
Oh, God, please don't let me die!
我的天哪!
Holy Christ!
我想联邦调查局 得再派一些人来了!
We're gonna need some more FBI guys, I guess.
真他妈的混蛋!
Jesus fucking Christ!
这是他妈的怎么回事?
What the fuck is going on?
你到底想怎么样? 坐在这儿看着大楼倒下去吗?
What are you gonna do? Sit here while the building falls down?
妈的!
Shit!
哦!好吧!
All right!
嘿！嘿！
Hey! Hey!
坚持住 宝贝
Hang on, baby.
坚持 宝贝
Hang on, honey.
哦 天哪
Oh, God.
汉斯!
Hans!
天哪
Jesus.
嗨，亲爱的
Hi, honey.
你们来就是为了这个? 他妈的抢劫?
So that's what this is all about? A fuckin' robbery?
把枪放下
Put down the gun.
为什么要炸掉整座大楼 汉斯?
Why'd you have to nuke the whole building?
如果你偷了六百块 你可以马上消失
Well, when you steal $600, you can just disappear.
如果你偷的是六亿 他们肯定能找到你
When you steal 600 million, they will find you
除非他们认为你已经死了
unless they think you're already dead.
把枪放下
Put down the gun.
不 他是我的
This is mine.
你赢了
You got me.
还是牛仔作风 麦克连先生
Still the cowboy, Mr McClane.
美国人都一样
Americans... all alike.
不过这次韦恩别想 和凯丽一起出去看落日了
This time, John Wayne does not walk off into the sunset with Grace Kelly.
应该是古柏 笨蛋
That was Gary Cooper, asshole.
玩笑开够了
Enough jokes.
你自己也能成为好牛仔 汉斯
You'd have made a pretty good cowboy yourself, Hans.
哦 是的 你以前对我是怎么说的
Oh, yes. What was it you said to me before?
去你妈的 王八蛋
Yippee-ki-yay, motherfucker.
荷莉!
Holly!
旅途愉快 汉斯
Happy trails, Hans.
希望那不是一名人质
I hope that's not a hostage.
这边 这个角度更好
Over here. It's a better angle.
帮他们一把
Let's give them a hand.
继续走 继续走
Keep it going, now. Keep it going.
- 快 我们要错过了 - 好 把笔记本给我
- Come on. We're going to miss it! - OK. Hand me my notes!
在那里怎么样？他们怎么对待你？
What was it like in there? How did they treat you?
这是我太太 荷莉
Al, this is my wife Holly.
荷莉·吉奈萝
Holly Gennero.
荷莉·麦克连
Holly McClane.
你好 荷莉
Hello, Holly.
你选了一个好丈夫
You got yourself a good man.
你要好好照顾他
You take good care of him.
麦克连
McClane!
麦克连 我要听你的解释! 我要你的解释!
McClane, I want a debriefing!
你必须回答一些问题 先生
You got some things to answer for, mister.
杀死艾利斯是一件
Ellis' murder, for one thing.
财产损失、妨碍警方公务
Property damage, interfering with police business.
没事啦!你们两个进去看看 还有没有别的人
Two of you go inside and see if there's anybody else!
哦 这是自己人!
No. This one's with me.
麦克连先生 麦克连先生!
Mr McClane, Mr McClane!
一切都结束了 经过这些折磨 你有什么感想?
Now that it's all over, after this incredible ordeal, what are your feelings?
看谁来了
Well, well, well.
- 圣诞快乐 阿盖 - 圣诞快乐
- Merry Christmas, Argyle. - Merry Christmas.
你拍下来了?
Did you get that?
如果这就是他们的圣诞节 我明年一定还来
If this is their idea of Christmas, I gotta be here for New Year's.